# DAVID E. VERNON

7402 North 85th Lane ~ Glendale, Arizona 85305 Phone (602) 549-8140 ~ Fax (602) 926-2276

E-mail Address: david@dvernon.com ~ Portfolio: http://portfolio.dvernon.com

# **About Me**

I have been working as an office manager for an importer for the last ten years. My responsibilities have included supervising office and sales staff, ordering and logistics of international container shipments, payroll, and all accounting of the business including taxes, receivables and payables. I am currently looking to get back into a computer related career in application development. I have worked doing web design and programming for many years. I have an extensive knowledge of computers and different languages. I am very proficient and a quick learner.

# **Computer Experience**

### **Web Development**

- HTML 14 years experience setting up web pages using HTML.
- Flash 10 years experience using Flash including ActionScript.
- PHP 12 years experience building web applications using PHP. Also have recently completed the course 'Web Scripting in PHP' at Estrella Mountain Community College.
- MySQL 12 years experience building web based databases with MySQL. Most of them have been integrated with PHP applications but have also used MySQL with VB.Net and C#.Net.
- ASP I built an online billing application a few years back using Visual InterDev 6 and have recently been working with it again using C#.
- Java Used and scripted Java in many web sites that I developed.
- CSS Have used CSS on a few sites. One was totally dependent on CSS for all its layout.

## **Application Development**

- Basic & Pascal Began learning programming in High School using Basic and Pascal.
- Visual Basic and VB.Net 16 years experience programming with Visual Basic on Visual Studio.
- C++ While attending DeVry University I took a class in C++. Didn't extensively use it outside of the class.
- C# 2 years ago I started learning C#. I self taught myself at first by rewriting applications that I had previously written using Visual Basic in C#. I have since then taken a class at Estrella Mountain Community College in C# and I am currently taking a Level II class at Rio Salado Community College.

### **Software Experience**

Experienced in the following software: Microsoft Visual Studio (most recent is 2010, I have 2012 and 2013 but have not used them in extent), Microsoft Office (including Word, Excel, Access, Outlook, and PowerPoint), Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Fireworks, Adobe Flash Professional, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, and QuickBooks.

#### **Hardware Experience**

Have worked mainly on PC but have worked a little with Mac. My home PC is custom built and have built my own for many years. I have experience in setting up small to mid size networks. I have also setup Windows and Linux Servers.

# RESUME OF DAVID VERNON CONTINUED...

# **Work Experience**

## 9/2002 to Present ~ Web Development and Programming ~ dvernon.com

Self-employed web site development and programming. I have a handful of clients that I picked up mainly by word of mouth that I work with during my spare time. Have done many web sites using Flash, CSS, Java, PHP, and MySQL.

# 3/2004 to Present ~ Office Manager ~ Majestic Stone Import

Working as the manager for an importer and distributor of Natural Stone Tile. Duties included taking care of payroll, supervising of office and sales staff, ordering and tracking of international shipments, accounts payable and receivable, and maintaining of books between multiple companies.

#### 2/2000 to 12/2003 ~ Internet, Video, & Phone Install Technician/Supervisor ~ Cox Communications

Worked as a contractor for Cox Communications doing residential & commercial cable installation. Installed video, internet, and telephone products. Worked as an install technician, trainer, lead technician, supervisor, and project manager.

#### 11/1999 to 2/2000 ~ Web/Database Design ~ Capture Quest, Inc.

Working independently for small company in development of web site. I designed and created a web based billing system using ASP with MS InterDev. The system I designed now allows credit card transactions to be processed over the web, with recurring payments, and user information to be logged in to a database on their server.

### 8/1999 to 12/1999 ~ Partner Support ~ Cable and Wireless USA / Campus CWIX

On temporary assignment through Norrell Services, I worked for the Cable and Wireless Campus Internet Service. My responsibilities there included helping them close that portion for their business by designing and programming in MS Access, Visual Basic 6.0, and various macro scripts that were used to help them with their closing and sale to another ISP. Twice the management team awarded me for my accomplishments and skills that helped them save time and manpower.

# 5/1999 to 8/1999 ~ Technical Support ~ Pridestaff / University of Phoenix

On temporary assignment through Pridestaff working at University of Phoenix for their Online Technical Support Group. Responsibilities include the assistance to students and faculty in problems they have with setting up and use of Microsoft Internet Explorer and Outlook with Online Classes.

This also includes helping them gain access to various web sites, mail accounts, and newsgroups used by the school for school information, classes, and e-mail. Knowledge of trouble shooting error messages, the Internet and Internet software, and setting up users on the MS Exchange Server was used to perform these tasks.

# **Education**

#### Estrella Community College, Avondale, AZ

Taking computer programming classes in order to be current on the latest languages and skills.

#### DeVry Institute of Technology, Phoenix, AZ

Completed three trimesters. Major Course of study is for a bachelor's degree in computer information systems. Dean's List for two of the trimesters.

## Phoenix Institute of Technology, Phoenix, AZ

Graduated in June 1987 with a certificate in architectural design and drafting.

## East Kentwood High School, Kentwood, MI

Graduated in June 1986. Extracurricular studies included computer programming, drafting, residential construction and architecture.